Guide to the Clarence Stein papers, 1905-1983.
Stein, Clarence papers
- Series II. Job Files
  - Job File
    - Kitimat, B.C. Report On Master Planning and City Development For The Aluminum Company of Canada. Part II of III: Detailed Discussion, Mayer and Whittlesey, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      city center, school system, transportation, utilities, neighborhoods
    - Kitimat, B.C. Report On Master Planning and City Development For The Aluminum Company of Canada. Part III of III: Consultants' Reports, Mayer and Whittlesey, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Ralph Eberlin, James C. Buckley, Inc., R. L. Davison
      reports
    - Kitimat First Neighborhood Center, 1952, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      design requirements, theater, school, letters, references
      Roger Willcox, J. E. Dudley, Albert Mayer
      notes, memos, plan, correspondence
    - Costs of city, government, housing -- Kitimat, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      J.E. Dudley, Walter E. Kroening
      outline, correspondence, memorandum
    - K.T.R. Health [Kitimat Townsite Report], 1952, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      health and medical care programs
      map, report
    - Housing -- Kitimat, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      J.E. Dudley
      plans, correspondence
    - Legal -- Kitimat, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      subdivisions of townsite
      C. McClelland Henderson (Al Co. of Ca. )
      United States Senate
      memo, legislative bill
    - Neighborhood Center, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      design requirements
      Albert May, Arthur Mayer, Englehardt, Louise Blackham, Humphrey Carver (Community Planning Association of Canada)
      notes, memos, correspondence
    - Neighborhood Community Design -- Kitimat letter exhibits only, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      report, memos, correspondence
    - Regulated Area -- Dudley letter, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      regulating activities in area around Kitimat, regional development and regulation
      Julian Whittlesey, Cyril McC. Henderson, James E. Dudley, Benton MacKaye, Roger Willcox
      Aluminum Company of Canada, Ltd.
    - Kitimat TPR article [Town Planning Review], 1953 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      plans for proposed town of Kitimat
      Gordon Stephenson
      correspondence, outline
    - Kitimat: Mayer And Whittlesey Reports and Correspondence, 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      observation, recommendations
      Albert Mayer, Julian Whittlesey, Cyril McC. Henderson, Percy E. Radley
      Mayer and Whittlesey, Northern Sentinel (Kitimat newspaper)
      reports, correspondence, memorandum, notes
    - Kitimat Townsite Development Programme 1955-1960 Related to Smelter Expansion To Potline #10, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      G.M. K. Davis
      report, map
    - Current Kitimat, 1952-1969 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      town design, directory of community organizations
      Roger Willcox, Julian Whittlesey, Cyril McC. Henderson (Municipal Manager Kitimat), J.B. White (VP of Aluminum Company of Canada Ltd.), J.E. Dudley
      1952-1953, 1955-1960, 1962,1964-1965, 1968-1969
      FCH Services, Inc.
      correspondence, articles, memos, pamphlet
    - [Untitled] Kitimat, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      files of Kitimat
      Julian Whittlesey (thru Mary L. Blair)
      correspondence, files, notes
    - Kitimat: Residential Neighborhoods, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      Ned and Muriel Ames (authors)
      paper, correspondence
    - Kitimat Maps and Plans (Box 3, Folder 22)
      land use, maps, town plans, recreational playgrounds
      1949-1957
      maps and plans
    - Maps-Kitimat, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      maps, photographs, plans, drawing list
    - M & W Master Plan Alcan, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      plan
    - Aluminium Limited Directors' Tour, July 24-August 9, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      photographs
  - JOBS, 1951, Kitimat Publicity
    - Kitimat Exhibit, 1955, Cities to Come, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      photographs, unbound pamphlet
  - PUBLICITY, PICTURES, ALCAN
    - Pictures -- Kitimat, 1952-1956 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      Eric F. West
      photographs, correspondence, press release
  - MAYER'S JOBS
    - Publicity -- Alcan, Pictures (in articles), 1944, 1953-1957 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      Julian Whittlesey
      articles, news clippings, correspondence
  - MAYER'S JOBS
    - Albert Mayer, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      Greater Bombay Master plan
      N.V. Kodak
      outline in bound form
    - Albert, Mayer -- East Punjab Capital: Chandigarh 1950, 1949-1950, 1961, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
      plans for capital city Chandigarh
      Shri P.L. Varma, Chief Engineer
      correspondence, plans, clipping, notes, outlines, reports, minutes, charts
    - Mayer, Albert, Newsletters (mimeographed), 1946-1952 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      India planning jobs and visits
      newsletters, memo
    - Mayer, Albert, Newsletter (mimeographed), 1953-1959 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      India planning jobs
      Frank Moraes
      newsletters
    - Mayer, Albert.: Delhi Plan Correspondence, 1956-1959 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      memo re: policy among planning policy brokers
      Gerald Breese (FF), Kenneth Iverson (Dir., Overseas Development Program)
      Ford Foundation
      correspondence, memo, outlines, reports, maps
    - Mayer, Albert: re India, 1956-1961 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      Gerald Breese
      correspondence, reports, programs
  - STEIN PROPOSED JOBS
    - Nat'1 Housing Corp., 1933, Surveys in [McKeesport2 Milwaukee, [Glendale] Alameda, and Valley Stream, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      blueprints, charts, correspondence, outlines, plans
  - VALLEY STREAM PROPOSED JOB, 1933
    - Cost of Building And Government, 1933, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      John O. Walker (Manager, Radburn Assoc. ), Charles S. Ascher
      estimates, correspondence
    - Survey of Valley Stream Long Island, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      pop., construction, housing
      Margaret Stein
      map, blueprint, draft
    - Proposed Housing Development, Valley Stream, N.Y., 1933 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      charts, blueprint, notes, maps
    - Valley Stream September 1933, 1933-1939 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      proposed housing development, Greenacres, description and financial set-up
      draft, sketches, maps, plans, article, report
  - PROPOSED JOBS
    - Army Housing Hawaii, 1941 (with Eberlin and Hardie Phillip), 1941, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Hardie Phillip, Ralph Eberlin
      U.S. Corps of Engineers
      memos, resumes, correspondence
  - PROPOSED JOBS, Maplewood Housing Project, 1943, Lake Charles, Louisiana
    - Maplewood, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      costs, proposed movie theatre, distribution, commercial facilities
      John W. Harris Associates, Gabriel Harmon (Chief, Land Planning Council, FHA), Samuel Ratensky
      correspondence, memos,reports
    - Maplewood, 1943, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      John W. Harris Associates
      pamphlet, plans, maps, blueprints, photographs
  - PROPOSED JOBS
    - Commercial facilities for Maplewood, Louisiana, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      report, including plans and blueprints
    - Public Facilities for Maplewood, Louisiana, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      1943
      plans, blueprints, report
  - PROPOSED JOBS, Fresh Meadow Park, 1944
    - Proposed Fresh Meadow Park Housing Development, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      proposal, financial set up, legal requirements
      plans, map, blueprints, reports, correspondent
  - PROPOSED JOBS
    - Fresh Meadow Park, 1944-1947 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      costs, golf course project, housing
      Robert Kohn, John W. Harris Associates, Inc.
      blueprints, notes, correspondence, memos, report
    - Fresh Meadows --Legal, Financial, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Satterlee, Warfield and Stephens
      notes, correspondence, memo
  - PROPOSED JOBS
    - N.Y. Life Insurance Co. (Box 4, Folder 9)
      proposed Fresh Meadows Park Housing Development 1944
      memos
  - PROPOSED JOBS
    - Fresh Meadow Golf Course (Box 4, Folder 10)
      memos, correspondence, map, notes
    - Report: By Harris, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      proposed housing for the Fresh Meadow Golf Course Area
      John Harris
  - PROPOSED JOBS
    - Operation Costs, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      limited dividend projects
      Ira S. Bobbins
      memos, correspondence
    - Estimates -- Harris, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 13)
      John W. Harris
      correspondence, memos, blueprints
    - Carlson, Carl, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      estimated costs of proposed Fresh Meadow Park housing development
      report, memo, blueprints, correspondence
  - PROPOSED FRESH MEADOW PARK HOUSING DEVELOPMENT
    - Harris- -Daiger, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      J.M. Daiger, J.W. Harris
      correspondence, memos, minutes
  - FMP, PROPOSED JOBS
    - Municipal Departments, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      cost estimates
      Board of Transportation
  - FMP
    - Construction Cost, Phipps #1, Hillside, 1936, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
      cost statement
  - FMP
    - Studies, 1941, 1944, undate (Box 4, Folder 18)
      estimated costs, construction, solar houses
      notes, charts, drawings, pamphlet
  - PROPOSED JOB
    - Fresh Meadow Park, 1944, 1947-1950 (Box 4, Folder 19)
      estimated income and expenses, tentative schedules, dwelling 'units
      Lewis Mumford
      charts, blueprints, articles
  - PJ, 1944
    - Gary -- Preliminary Investigation. Job No. P-251, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      industrial development plan, planning
      Gary Land Company, Carnegie -- Illinois Steel Corp.
      report, correspondence, bulletin, outlines, memos
  - PROPOSED JOBS, 1949
    - Rochester (Temple Bethel), Ade and Todd, Architects, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      drawings, correspondence
  - PROPOSED JOBS
    - Columbus Circle (M. Nowicki's photographs of model 1949 on, 1948-1964 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      Matthew Nowicki, Lewis Mumford
      1948-1949, 1952-1954, 1964
      Citizen's Union, Mayer and Whittlesey
      photographs, correspondence, articles, press releases
  - PROPOSED JOB, 1951
    - Stanford University, 1951-1954 (Box 4, Folder 23)
      Wallace Sterling (Pres,), Lewis Mumford, Paul Opperman
      report, including maps, correspondence, drafts
  - PROPOSED JOBS
    - Oakland Housing, 1954-1955 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Toward New Towns For America [pages missing], 1951 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      hard cover book
    - Towards New Towns For America, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 25a)
      Clarence S. Stein
      soft cover book
    - Public Administration Service Correspondence Regarding Toward New Towns (Symons, ed.), 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      PAS distribution of TNT
      F. Symons (Chief of Publications)
    - Reviews of 1951 Ed. of Towards New Towns, 1951, 1950-1954, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 27)
      F.J. Osborn
      listing, articles, clippings
    - Towards New Towns, 1951, Letters of comment, praise, and criticism, 1949-1954 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      Lewis Mumford, Hardie Phillips, Hale Walker, Albert Mayer, Ernest Scofield, Alexander Bing, Gorden Stephenson
      correspondence, article
    - Town Planning Review Correspondence, 1949-1952 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      TNT and Stein article for TPR
      Gorden Stephenson
      University of Liverpool
    - Business Correspondence On TPR and Book "Toward New Towns For America", 1951, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 30)
      book pricing and sales
      Gordon Stephenson, Farrell Symons
      University Press of Liverpool, Public Administration Service
    - Toward New Towns: Post-Publication, 1953, 1957-1973 (Box 4, Folder 31)
      reproduction rights and copyrights
      1957-1958, 1961-1962, 1973
    - Republication of Toward New Towns For America, 1955, 1953-1955 (Box 4, Folder 32)
      negotiations re publishing house transfer
      W.W. Atkins, Myle Wright (L.U.), J.C. O'Kane (L.U. Pres.), Gorden. Stephenson
      Liverpool University Press, Public Administration Service
      correspondence, notes
    - Contact: TNTA. 2nd Edition, Reinhold, 1956-1963, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 33)
      royalty statements
      William Wilson Atkins (Ed. Art and Architect!}] Books, Reinhold)
      Reinhold Book Division, Reinhold Publishing Company
      correspondence, vouchers, notes
    - (Preface -- Toward New Towns For America) Kitimat: Coordinated Planning Proposed for Functional-Operation Programs X-56, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 34)
      planned development and agriculture, Kitimat notes, preface
      outline, notes, manuscript drafts
    - Promotion Republication of TNTA, November 1956, 1957, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
      five copies distribution
      J.C.O'Kane
      Liverpool University Press, Reinhold Publishing
      correspondence, notes, lists, promotional material
    - Toward New Towns For America Reviews, 1957 Edition, 1957, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 36)
      Stuart Chase, Gorden Stephenson, Carl Feiss, F.J. Osborn, Lewis Mumford, George Butler, John Cans
      correspondence, articles, promotional material.
    - Toward New Towns For America Books and Magazines Sent To, 1950-1962 (Box 4, Folder 37)
      Ralph Eberlin, Herbert Emmerich
      correspondence, list
    - Toward New Towns: Requests To Republish Extracts, 1961, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Permission for reprint in TPR article and Book "Toward New Towns for America", 1949-1955, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Kitimat Article: Permission to Sue, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 40)
      "Architectural Forum"
    - Correspondence Regarding TNTA -- MIT Press, Reinhold, R. Willcox, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 41)
      republication of TNTA
      Roger Willcox, Wallace Campbell (Press. FCH)
      Foundation For Cooperative Housing, Inc.
    - TNTA -- Contract with Reinhold, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 42)
      Reinhold Publishing Company
      correspondence, contract
    - Toward New Towns Pre-Publication photographs for M.I.T. Press and Corrections, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 43)
      correspondence, proofs, bibliography
    - Commendations and Reviews TNTA, 3rd MIT Edition, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 44)
      Albert Mayer, Charles S. Ascher
      articles, reviews, correspondence
  - TOWARD NEW TOWNS IN AMERICA
    - Toward New Towns: MIT Edition Sales, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 45)
      sales and royalties
      M.I.T. Press
      correspondence, memo
    - TNTA (MIT) Books Ordered for Friends, 1966-1969 (Box 4, Folder 46)
      MIT Press
      correspondence, vouchers, lists
    - Toward New Towns for America, Jackets, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
      book jackets
    - Toward New Towns: Italian Rights Mondadori Publ., 1965, 1965-1969 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - TNTA -- Japan, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 49)
      Translation of TNTA
    - Photographs: Republication of Toward New Towns, 1949-1967 (Box 4, Folder 50)
      Lewis Wilson, Gordon Stephenson, Gretchen Van Tassel (photographer)
      1949, 1955-1957, 1961, 1964, 1967
      correspondence, lists, memo
    - [Untitled] Radburn, Greenbelt, 1930, 1955, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 51)
      Radburn, Greenbelt
      plans, photographs, list of missing plans
    - MIT photographs Sunnyside, ca. 1966 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Plans and Drawings used in TNTA, #'s in folder, 1927-1966, unadted (Box 4, Folder 53)
      Greenbelt, Hillside
      1927, 1955, 1964-1966, undated
      plans, drawings, correspondence
    - Radburn -- Plans, Maps, 1929-1960, undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
      1929, 1932, 1960, undated
      negatives, photographs, maps, correspondence
    - The Radburn Plan and Map, 1929, undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
      1929, undated
      plans, maps
    - Radburn, undated (Box 4, Folder 55a)
      photographs, map, plans
    - Greenbelt, undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - T.N.T. -- Greenbelt From G. Van Tassel, 1946, 1956, undated (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Greendale, undated (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Greenhills, undated (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - photographs #52-67 Chatham Village, MIT, 1966, ca. 1966, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 60)
      photographs, correspondence, clipping, article
    - Phipps, undated (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Hillside (Box 4, Folder 62)
      ca. 1933, undated
    - MIT 1966 photographs Baldwin Hills Village (Box 4, Folder 63)
      ca. 1966
    - Valley Stream (Box 4, Folder 64)
      1933
      map
- Series III. Writings and Speeches
  - Index to addresses and additional articles by CSS (Box 5, Folder 1)
    1921-1960
  - "Reviews by CSS (not indexed) 1921, 1932, 1934" (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Review for The Nation: Slums, large Scale Housing and Decentralization, Vol. III. President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership. E-2-1932, Patrick Abercrombie, Town and Country Planning, 1932
    Patrick Abercrombie, Prof. of Civic Design, University of Liverpool
    1932, 1934
  - "Journal of the AIA, 1918-1923 Octagon, June 1933" (Box 5, Folder 3)
    see listing -- articles on planning and housing
    1918-1923, 1933
  - "The Housing Problem" in Women and The Cities Work, Dec. 6, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    1919-1920
  - "The Housing Crisis in New York, 1920-, The Survey, Sept. 1, 1920" (Box 5, Folder 5)
    1920
  - "To Solve The Housing Problem ... in Sunday World, June 20, 1920 (by Dr. L. Levine about CSS)" (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Dr. Louis Levine
  - "Housing Problems. Articles in Better Times, Nov. 1920, Oct. 1920, Jan. 1921" (Box 5, Folder 7)
    1920-1921
    Better Times
  - "AIA Comm. on Comm. PI. Benton MacKaye: Project for Appalachian Trail" (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Appalachian Trail planning
    Benton MacKaye
    1921, 1965, 1968, 1972
    correspondence, articles
  - "AIA Comm. on Comm. PI. C.S. Stein: Amsterdam Old and New, 1922" (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Comparison of methods, editorials
    1922
    New York Times, Post, Globe
  - Articles by CSS of AIA, 1922-1923 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    "600 Million more for Transit in NY," 9-4-22 "Future of our Big Cities," Jan. 1923 "Secretary's Table," Apr. 1922 "Housing and Reconstruction" "Housing and the Depression" "Plan for Creative Housing"
    1922-1923,
  - "Congestion of Population: in Medical Records, talk given, Academy of Medicine, Feb. 16, 1922" (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Population congestion
    New York Academy of Medicine
  - "The Housing Shortage, The Survey, Apr. 15, 1922 Housing shortage (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - "Housing New York's Two-Thirds. The Survey, 1923-1924", ca. 1923-1924 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Housing needs
  - "Bing-Stein-Wright-Study of Proposed Garden Community 1923", 1923 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Proposed Garden suburb
    Alexander M. Bing, Henry Wright
    study (2 copies)
  - "Sunnyside and the Housing problem, 1924 City Housing Corporation", ca. 1924 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    apartment plans
  - "AIA Rpt. of Committee on Community Planning 1924-1922", 1924-1928 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    community planning
    American Institute of Architects
  - "AIA Journal Reprint by Committee on Community Planning on Architecture and Broad Planning by several (Unwin, Mumford etc.) 1925-1926, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Architecture and Broad planning
    Raymond Unwin, Lewis Mumford, Frederick Bigger, C.H.W.
  - "Survey Graphic, Regional Plan Member, May 1925 contains Dinosaur Cities by C.S. Stein", 1925 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Dream city vs. Reality
  - "Cooperative Housing, The Architect's Viewpoint, address at Cooperative League, 1925", 1925 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Cooperative Housing
    Fourth Co-operative Congress of the Co-operative League of America
  - "Savings and Loan Assn. and its Relation to Housing Problem, address at Jamestown Convention, 6/25", 1925 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    The Savings and Loan Association, housing problems
    New York State League of Savings and Loan Associations
  - "Wanted: A Place to Play in The Playground, Nov. 25/25 (Sunnyside)", 1925 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    playgrounds
  - "Commission of Housing and Regional planning report, New York State", 1920-1931 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    housing situation, N.Y. state
    State of New York
  - "Housing the People", The Nation, March 10, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    Improving housing conditions
    New York State
  - "Nobody's business (Low- Income Housing)" The Standard, March 1926 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    low-income housing
  - "Community Planning of Homes" American Federationist, March 1926 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    Home planning, community planning
  - "A Tenement House Law for the Rich", The Survey, January 15, 1929 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    Tenement House Law
    New York Tenement House Commission
  - "Building Homes as Unit Project Gives Harmony", N.Y. Herald Tribune, September 14, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    neighborhood
  - "The President's Housing Conference -- A Challenging Opportunity", American City, November & December 1930 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    Housing
    Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership
  - "Housing and Common Sense", The Nation and reprint from Reader's Digest, May 11 and October 1932 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    standards of house construction
  - "An Outline for Community Housing Procedure", Architectural Forum, May 1932 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    community housing procedure
  - "A. I. A. Report of Committee on Economics of Site, Planning and Housing, 1932 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    site planning, housing
  - "Radburn and Sunnyside", photographs, Architectural Forum, March 1932 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    Radburn and Sunnyside
  - "Housing Policy for the United States Government", by RPAA, Octagon, June 1933 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    housing policy
    Regional Planning Association of America
  - "New Towns for A New Age", N.Y. Times Magazine, October 8, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    New Town development
  - "The Planned Community", Architectural Forum, April 1933 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    planned communities
    report, charts, pictures
  - "Housing and the Depression", Octagon, Journal of A. I. A., 1933 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    housing, the depression
  - "Restrictive Housing vs. Constructive Housing", (conversation) Architecture, May 1933 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    housing, restrictive vs. constructive
    Marshall L. Oliver
  - "Store Buildings and Neighborhood Shopping Center", 1934 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    stores, shopping centers
    Catherine Bauer
    articles, preliminary studies
  - "Store Buildings and Neighborhood Shopping Centers", 1934 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    shopping centers, planning
    studies, charts, reports
  - "The Price of Slum Clearance", Architectural Forum, February 1934 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    slum clearance, land costs
  - "Hillside Homes", American Architect, February 1936 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    apartments
  - "The Wagner Act of 1937", American Architect and Architecture, November 1937 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    federal housing legislation
    Coleman Woodbury, Langdon Post, Albert Mayer
  - "Housing; The Next Chapter, for A. I. A. News Release, 1937", 1937 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    housing, political issue
    carbon copy manuscripts
  - "The Gardens of Souchow", Pencil Points, July 1938 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    garden courts, photographs
  - "The Case for New Towns", Planners' Journal, March-June 1939 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    new towns
  - "Public Housing Management", 1940 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    management of public housing, Hillside Homes
  - "Investment Housing Pays", Survey Graphic, February 1940 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    subsidized housing
  - "Harbor Hills Housing", Pencil Points, November 1941 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    apartment complex
  - "Housing for Defense for Common Sense", April 1941 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    housing emergency
  - "City Patterns, Past and Future", New Pencil Points, June 1942 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    city patterns
  - "Preparedness for Post-war Urban Redevelopment", American City, February 1942 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    housing, community development
  - "The Future of New York", Mimeographed, May 1943 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    opportunities in New York City
    Hanes Committee Report to Gov. Dewey
    mimeo manuscript, newspaper clippings
  - "County of London Plan" Comments, in Architectural Review, London, September 1944 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    rebuilding London
    carbon copies of manuscripts